11482 Lowell Ave, Overland Park, KS 66210 email: ray@rayjnorris.com

cell: 913 522-3611

Summary

Senior Software Development Manager with 25+ years experience leading large scale software automation projects using Agile practices.

Accomplishments

I have acumen in Mortgage Lending Automation across the Origination Channel with considerable focus in Automated Underwriting processes and support systems.

I led the development of the first internet based Automated Underwriting system for Residential Mortgage Lending.

I have broad experience with Financial Systems, Healthcare, and Manufacturing.

I lead and practice Lean Development, Kanban, Scrum project management methodologies including strong customer focus and participation.

Current Concentrations

- ✓ Software Automation Project Management and Leadership
- ✓ Digital Marketing Strategy and Development
- ✓ Mortgage Lending Business Systems

Experience

RayJNorris.com Consultancy 2009-Present

Stonegate Mortgage Corp, project manager/ business analyst 2014-15

Led development of an internet based Non-Agency Eligibility system for Stonegate's origination channel(s). The system provides sub-second multi-investor guideline evaluation and approval returns.

Digital Marketing / Website Development engagements:

HappyValleyFidders.org, 2015-16 SOSRide.org, 2015-16 CapitusGroup.com, 2013-14 MetropolitanReporters.com, 2010 TheWayWomenWork.com, 2009 InnovaPrep.com, 2010-14

Salva O'Renick, director of digital interactive 2008

Introduced Digital Marketing skills, strategy, and operations into the organization. Implemented SCRUM based Agile development and project management; implemented CRM based opportunity and sales management using Salesforce.com.

First Horizon Home Loans, Inc., chief managing consultant 2005 – 2006 Created and staffed the Information Technology organization at First Horizon Home Loans; delivered FAMUS, First Horizon's first web-based Loan Origination system.

Novastar Financial, Inc. senior vice president, 1997 – 2004

Created and staffed the Information Technology organization at Novastar Financial Inc.; delivered fourteen business systems, most notably the first web-based Subprime Loan Origination systems; opened six large offices, instrumental in growing the business from startup to a multi-billion dollar business.

Saxon Mortgage, Inc., senior vice president, 1991 – 1996 Created and staffed the Information Technology organization at Saxon Mortgage, Inc.; delivered SOLO (Saxon Online Loan Origination) system, instrumental in growing the business from startup.

Education

Business Information Systems Degree, 3.91 GPA 1985 United States Air Force, Radio Relay, Secret Security Clearance 1973 – 1975